우린 복제인간이야
누군가의 실험물이고지금은 우릴 죽여버리고 있지!
난 베스가 아니야
베스가 이 살인범의 목록에올라있었지, 지금은 나야
누군가 자기네 불법 실험을 감추려고우릴 쓸어버리고 있어
사라가 오늘 밤 못가면 키아라를영영 못데려 올 수도 있어
걔 나보고 자기 딸 앞에서자기 흉내를 내라는 거야?
아줌만 우리 엄마 아니에요너한테는 미안하지만
네가 비밀로 해주는게정말로 중요해
저게 내 남자친구였으면,나라도 기차앞에 뛰어들었을꺼야
뭔가 달라
여기 아무일 없는거지?얘가 아무일 없는것처럼 보이세요?!
저기, 우리 둘이서 함께 시간 좀보내자. 갑자기 우리가
어떻게 된건지 찾아보자. 왜나면 이런 것들도나 좋아하거든. 아주 많이
사라가 내 뒤통수를 쳤어그러더니 코크를 훔쳐갔지
나 파우치한테걸려있단 말야!
매기가 널 만드는걸 도왔었어
베스는 우릴 보호하려고그 여잘 죽인거네
우린 연결되있어너 느껴지니?
가, 도망쳐!
그만두겠어요
쉬. 쉬. 쉬
토마스
일단은 쉬어라
자거라, 아가야
자거라
그래, 살인자는 아직도살아있는거네
그래, 아마도 우리를 쫓도록그앨 보낸 곳으로 기어들어갔겠지
경찰짓하던거꼭 관둬야 했던거야?
그게 무슨 도움이 되겠어앨리슨, 전화한건
그거 때문이 아니라너한테 고맙다고 하고싶어서
키아라 일로도와준거 말야
아
그래, 내일 아이 만나잖아
그게, 어, 네가 자릴 마련해줘서.. 머, 정말 특별한 아이야
넌 정말 운이 좋은거라고말해줄께
안돼
저기!베스! 잠깐, 나야!
오, 놀래라. 무슨 짓이야!손톱줄로 내 눈을 찌르려던거야?
그래, 샤워하는데 몰래 들어오면손톱줄로 눈을 찔러줘야지!
너 코디네 집에있기로 한거 아니였어?
널 겁주려던건 아니였어미안해
얼마나 미안한데?
베스
들어와
우리 떠나자
너 경찰도 나왔고
나도 내 일이 싫어
우리 짐싸자
지금 바로
나 진심이야
우리 아침에 얘기하자
탐지기에 이게 떴어깨어나고 있어
깨어나지 못하게해
당장!그냥 집어넣어!
Orphan Black 01x05Conditions of Existence
Original Air Date  April 27, 2013
한글자막 :  Nike Plus
깼어, 커피 마실레?
어, 난 됐어
기분은 어때?
뭐가?
총도 없고, 뱃지도 없고어디 갈데도 없고
우리 떠나자
묶여있을거없잖아
널 위한 딱 세 마디해줄 말이 있어
폴리오 드 자이네루(브라질휴양지)
당장은 그냥 떠날 수 없지만리오 가는건 생각해볼께
왜 안되지?
네가 원했던거잖아, 아냐?서로에 헌신, 나 준비됐어
아니, 나 지금 당장은그런 생각 못하겠어
뭐 잘못됐어?잘못된건 없어
사시나무 떨듯떨고 있잖아
지금은어디가는데?
그냥 바람 좀 쐐러나가는거야. 됐지
뇌전도 검사장치에서나온 전극이야
뭐라고?
EEG 헬멧, 뇌내전기적 활동을 감시하는 거지
그렇담 지랄맞은 꿈을 꾼게아니란거네, 그치?
이럴 줄 알았어저기, 내가 얼마나
얘기 했었어? 우린 불법 실험에실험실 생쥐 꼴이라니까
사라, 그러는 동안에폴은 어딨었어?
어.. 그중에 둘 셋은
음, 의사들이였었고아마도 안에
있깄 있었겠지
아마 녀석이준비했을껄
저기, 누군가는 반드시 실험용 쥐를감시해야지.. 우리가 아는 누구
머, 내 말은, 내가실험한거라면, 그래 나라도
대상물 가까이에관찰자를 두었을꺼야..
그찮아, 누군가는 색인표를 달고데이터를 모아야지
코지마..나한테 무슨 짓을 한걸까?
내 생각엔 그들이 뭔가진짜로..
음, 칼을 댔다던지 하면너도 알았을꺼야
이런 젠장할말이 그렇단 거지, 음
EEG는 뇌활동 측정같은거고
팔에 있는 자국으로 봐선.. 혈액표본 채취했을꺼야
분석을 위한거 같에폴도 끼어있는거야?
모르겠어왜?
너랑 같이 잤다고 그런거야?피
그래, 그러다보니까쿵쿵대고 그랬다
야 너좀 복잡해지는데
너 베스 남자친구랑잔거야?
난 그럴리가 없겠지만
나도 어쩜 감시자하고자고 있을지도 모르겠다
부탁한 총 저기 뒀어난 가야겠어
이봐, 이봐돈은 어딨어?
뭐에 쓰려고?
우리 보호 기금이잖아아니야?
지난 번 확인했을 때,우릴 보호하는건 나 하나 뿐이고
2만 달러야
제발 현명하게 써줘
그래, 영수증 보내줄께
폴 그 자식 알을쏴버리겠어
잠깐, 그냥, 음..비틀어버리기만 해, 알았지?
이 모든 일에우릴 데려다 줄꺼야
하지만, 만약내 눈먼 실험물이 갑자기..
자각을 하게되면, 이것 또한유레카적 순간이지만..
그래?
나라면 폐기하겠어그러니까..
조심해, 알았지?
적어 둘께..
젠장
경찰서야, 오늘만 세번째네안돼, 받지마
어, 아트, 뭐 필요하세요?
저 라지에요
저 그만 뒀어요라지
알아요괜찮으세요?
예예, 그럼, 제가 빌려드린
그 감시장치들 아시죠?
재고조사 들어가기 전에제가 돌려놔야되서요
감시장치들요?맞다, 맞다
그래고, 베스저한텐 터놓고 말하시죠
그거 폴 때문이죠그렇죠?
저기, 저 이틀안에돌려줄께요, 됐죠?
그럼, 베스가 감시장비를가지고 있었단거네
그렇단건 걔도 폴을의심하고 있었던거네
궁금한건 말이지그애가 뭔가를 발견했을까?
중요한겁니다
한 주는 괜찮다가도다음 주면 아마게돈이죠
아뇨, 저도 이해합니다그래도 전 그녀가 반응할만한
원인을 제공하고 싶진 않아요
저기당신이 얘기했잖소!
상황이 더 악화되면다른 방법은 뭐가 있죠?
당신 뭐하는 거야?
나중에 다시 전화할께
다..당신 왜내 화장대 뒤지는거야?
그게.. 가위 찾느라
당신 누구랑통화한거야?
방금 말야?
어, 빅 리치, 회사에서내 얘길?
수잔 텔러 때문에. 이번 분기에그 여자가 우릴 다 넘어섰거든
당신도 알잖아
오, 잘됐다. 음이 상표 좀 잘라줄레?
날 미치게 한다니까
훨씬 낫네
그래 좋아, 그가 들어오면우린 어떻할껀데?
쏴버려야지
농담이야
그냥.. 감시장치나 찾어알았지?
그리고 찾아본거는다 제자리에 돌려놓고
여기 소독되있겠지
이젠 폴의 모든게가짜인 것 같네
뭐가?
빈집털이 할 때지문을 남기면 안된다고
트렉스콤 자문회사
만약, 어, 가짜 폴이베스를 관찰하는 거였으면
어떻게 사라 매닝을 관찰한사람이 절대 없다고 확신할 수 있는거지?
누구? S 부인은 날 미워하고일년 동안 만나지도 않았는데
그리고 너야 미심적어도믿어줄만 하니까
신임 득표 하나 받았네
베스 컴퓨터엔 아무것도 없어전혀 없네
음성 파일도, 동영상도녹취기록도 없어
이런 망할
헤이, 헤이, 헤이
이 자식 군인이네
보아하니 비밀을 가진게너만은 아니였나보네
그건 또 뭐야?
베스가 보낸 편지야
폴한테? 나도 읽어보고 싶다아, 아, 아
안돼사생활이잖아
이 망할 감시장비는어딨는거야?
모르겠어우리가 다 찾아봤잖아
어디 볼까나
얘 빈둥대고있던건아니였네, 그치?
이번엔 폴이 일하는데를찾아볼 차롄거 같네
오, 그래트렉스콤 자문회사
가짜 폴가짜 회사
거기 아무것도 없다는데내가 돈 건다
이럴리가
베스
사무실 축소해서요기억하죠?
폴 사무실은이제 이쪽이에요
아, 그렇죠
예, 당연하죠
지금 회의 중인데요
어, 이.. 있잖아요
음.. 저희가 아침에좀 그랬었거든요
화해하자고점심 좀 싸왔어요
오세요
저 그냥..
그러세요
왕가슴 숨결?
필릭스너한테 이거
들리면 좋겠는데 그래! 그래 들려
멍청한 언니야이제 엉덩이 끌고 나가야지?
점심 가지고 온거네그래
화평 제의야
베스, 오늘 아침엔..너 그 얘기 하고싶어?
난 어제밤 얘기면더 좋겠는데
샤워할 때.. 폴
나 점심 가지고 온거야그거 뿐이라고
우리 사이뭔가 변했어
너도 분명느끼고 있겠지
너 상처어떻게 된거야?
뭐가?
산악자전거 사고로목에 상처가 생겼잖아
사라졌어
어, 정말로?
로..로션을 바꿨거든
한번 보자
뭐든지 해보려는구나?그럴레?
그럴꺼야
근데 일하러돌아가봐야돼
점심 고마워
저녁에 봐그러지
메디슨
오후 스케쥴 비워놔알았지?
일이 좀 생겼어 젠장
앨리슨당신 뭐하는거야?
어..
상자에 뭐가 들어있어도니?
개인물건이야
아니, 아니야!뭐.. 뭐가 들어있어?
도니, 상자에 뭐있냐고?나도 사생활은 좀 있어야지
집에서라도 말이야아, 그래서 리치가 당신한테 연락한거네
그건 또 무슨 뜻으로 하는 소리야?상자 열어봐, 도니!
이리 내놔!열어!
앨리슨..앨리슨, 그만 못해!
좋아, 혈액은 좋아보여감염도 없고
어떤 증상에 대해얘기하는 건데?
음.. 호흡이 짧아지고피를 토하고..
그런거 말이야
대상이 누구야?어, 여럿이야, 그리고 얘길하면
내가 널 죽여야만 하거든하! 하..
하! 하!음, 이 표본들
중합효소연쇄반응 좀 돌려보고무슨 유전적 표식이
나타나나 봐주겠어?니 생각엔..
항트립신 결핍?낭포성 섬유증?
그치, 뭐 그런거
그래고, 음, 씨토크롬-C배열도 확인해줄 수 있지?
바코드 유전자 말야?으-흠
그거 종을 구분할 때사용하는 거잖아
그런가?
나한텐뭐가 있는데?
음, 섹스라면어떻겠어?
너 혼자서..
그..그거끝내준다
미안하다
이거 아주 개자식이네
누구?
폴, 베스는그 녀석 사랑했어
근데 사랑을 받아주지도 않았고또 그앨 떠나지도 않았어
음, 머, 이제 녀석 확실히목소리가 바꼈던데, 안그래?
사라, 녀석 너한테빠져들고 있어
이런, 이게 뭐람
난 키아라 학교 밖이야
지금 당장 날 두렵게하는거 모든 것 중에.. 피
이게 가장 힘든거야 그애 너 보려고
기다릴 수 없는건 알지, 그치?그래, 고마워
진짜로 중요한 건아이 하나 뿐이야, 너도 알지?
알지음, 나도 사랑한다 해줘, 알았지?
콜린안녕
발길을 옮겨줘서 너무 기쁘네요영안실에서요?
어, 제 말 믿어요일정같은건 사실 문제도 아니에요
안녕
이번엔엄마 맞단다
알아요
세상에, 내가 너얼마나 보고 싶었는데
저도 보고싶었어요
왜 그렇게예쁜 옷 입었어요?
너 작은것도 놓치지 않는구나그치?
엄마, 괜찮아요?
그래
지금은 좋아
이런, 너 컸네
제가 반에서제일 작아요
그래도, 나한테는크거든
어떻게 앨리슨 고모 얘기는한번도 안하실 수 있어요?
나도 몰랐었단다
딱 엄마처럼 생겼어요
그래
언젠가, 전부 설명해줄께알았지, 우리 원숭이?
누가 우리를다치게 해요?
그건 왜 묻는거니?
고모가 엄마는 안심하고살수 있게 하고 있다고 했어요
얘, 얘야
아니야
넌 안전하다, 키아라약속해
알았지?
너 들어올꺼니?
저기, 미안한데
너 방금 실험실에 이거두고가서. 미안
고마워
근데.. 까놓고 얘기할께내가, 음, 살짝 봤거든
너 프랑스애지
너 성적죽여주더라고
고마워
음, 음, 어, 이런정말 미안하다
내가 보통은이. 이러지 않는데
어, 안좋게 깨졌어?
그래, 그치, 우리태평양만큼 떨어져있으니..
그래장거리가 다 그렇더라고
음, 너도 미생물학이지맞아?
그래, 음, 면역학이야숙주와 기생체 관계를 연구하고있어
오, 좋다, 멋지네그래, 난 진발이야
진화적 발육학
그래, 머, 우..우리가 그렇게 불러서
그래그래
델피네야코지마야
Enchant?e만나서 반갑다
너 혼자서도 잘하네안그래?
흠, 원숭아?
작은 원숭이?누가 떠오르지 않니?
예, 그래도 전 성이나있었죠, 안그래요?
작은 일에도요
어쨌거나, 아줌마가 저한테펑크락을 알려주신 분이죠
그래, 넌 거기 모든방식을 받아들였고
사상은 쏙 빼놓고
저 애가 저처럼 이리저리튀어다니지 않는 것만으로도 행복해요
제가 아줌마랑 같이런던에서 산게
저 나이였었죠, 예?좀 더 들어서였지
머, 절 여기까지데려오시기도 했고요
저도 알아요
그래도, 아직 아줌마도움이 필요해요
저한테 얘기 좀해주세요, 어..
제가 정말로어디서 왔는지 정말로
아는거 없으세요?
지금와서 왜?일들을 정리해보고 있어요
키아라를 위해서요아시겠죠?
넌 위탁기관에 있었지애들 중에서 데려왔다
알다시피, 난 부모님이누구였는진 모른다
예, 저도 벌써..프릭스톤에 가정복지기관과
얘기해 봤어요그래도 궁금한건
다른게 없는냐는 거죠별일 없는거지?
네
네, 전 괜찮아요
빅은 어떠니?
빅도 네 그림에 포함되니?그럴리가요
그것만큼은 약속드릴께요빅은 끝났어요
알았다고!
좀 어떠세요, 대장?뵈니까 반갑네요
파우치 씨
파우치 씨, 그 년이기차로 뛰어들었다고요
왜 그랬는지는 저도모른다고요, 아시겠어요?
물론, 우리도 좋았다 나빴다해도다 좋았지 않습니까
그 년이 코크도가져갔어요
그러다보니아마도 경찰이
가지고 있겠죠일주일만 주세요
파우치 씨, 돈은가져다 드릴께요
지난 주에도그렇게 떠들었지!
알아요. 저 쓸만하잖아요잠깐만요
저 잘하잖아요, 파우치 씨저 아시잖아요, 파우치 씨, 제발
잠깐만요, 파우치 씨, 일주만 더요돈 갖다 드릴께요, 형님! 알았어요!
알았어 알았어요!
파우치 씨, 제발요! 일주일만 더요형님! 예, 좀 기다려봐요!
알았어요!좋아요, 알았다고요!
좋아요! 돈 필요하세요? 좋아, 좋아요!잠깐만요!, 제가 바로..
괜찮아요
다왔다
각자 초코렛하나씩이다
그뿐이다
됐지?
동생 손잡고 가야지
알겠지? 누구하고도얘기하면 안된다
네에네에, 엄마
사랑한다
저도 사랑해요녜, 엄마
어, 방지하려고요아님 감시하려고요?
감시장비로, 부탁해요
작은 걸로요
이런거 말씀하시는건가요?어, 이정도? 무선이고, 적당하죠
유모캠이라고부른답니다
가끔은 유모들이 값나가는걸손대거든요
가끔은 남편들이 유모를손대기도 하고요, 아시죠?
어떻게 동작하는지나보여주세요, 부탁드려요
학교 잘다녀라
이렇게된단다친구야
사라?
사라
이봐, 사라
사라너 살아있네!
사라, 나야!
날 보라고
어, 저.. 전..
당신이 누군지 몰라요
이 개년, 속이려고?지금 사람 잘못 보신거에요
날 속이네, 이 개년아!어떻게 나한테 이럴 수 있어?!
사라, 너가죽은 줄 알았다고!
빌어먹을 니가 어떻게 이러냐고?아! 아악!
내 눈!아, 너 이년!
아! 이 망할 것!여기들 오네
망할! 죽어버려!와라. 경주하자. 차에 타
차에타는 경주하는거야사라!
됐다, 먼저타는사람이 이기는거야!
저 아저씨 누구에요?아! 사라!
됐다
야 개년아!
여보세요, 앨리슨나 방금 역겨운 건달한테
폭행 당했어너 아는 사람인가봐
누구? 어떻게 생겼는데?모르겠어, 생긴건..
도시풍이던데
젠장 그건 뭔 소리야?
하얗지 않은거알겠어?
이런, 젠장빅?
어떻게 됐어?
어떻게 됐긴내가 되갚아 줬지
제발 그 자식이키아라 아빠란 말은 말아줘
아니, 아냐절대로 아니야
그럼, 폴이랑은어떻게 돼가?
그게, 베스가 그를감시했었던거 같에
감시장비를 찾았어
걔 그런 얘기는전혀 안했는데
그게 사실이야?그가 쥐새끼일까?
아직 그건 모르겠고
너는 어떻게 지내?
별거없어괜찮아
뭐 확실한게 있으면전화해줘
올리비에 씨
폴
여기서 뭐하시는거죠?무슨 문제있습니까?
베스일로 얘기좀 나눠야겠네
그여자 오늘 아침엔어떻던가?
괜찮았죠
별일 없었어요
너 이런거 별로잘 못하는구나, 그치?
살아있는 사람 말이야?
오! 하!
영안실 농담이네
끔찍히도 귀엽네
그럼그럼
잘있어
잘가
영안실 직원이랑?진짜로?
노크 좀 하시지?끝내준다, 피
우리가 내 시체 신원사기 쳤던자식이랑 쿵쿵대다니
콜린은 오랜만에 만난진짜 멋진 남자라고
뭐, 한 6주 됐냐?
아니, 적어도 8주이건 어떻게 될꺼라고
생각하는거야, 어?오, 이럴수가
아, 미안 미안. 내가 완전잊고있었네. 규칙 제 일번 :
언제나 네 인생이 나보다 중요하다아니야, 그냥..
더 복잡한거 뿐이지빅이 돌아왔어
오, 젠장
그래, 녀석이 앨리슨이랑 마주쳤어그래서 내가 살아있는 줄 알아
내가 해결해야지. 내가..폴 사무실에서
무슨 일이 있었는지 알고싶은데미안, 내가 좀 바빴어서, 그찮아?
머, 내가 뭐 좀녹음해 뒀는데
여기서 뭐하시는거죠?무슨 문제있습니까?
바로 이거야
베스일로 얘기좀 나눠야겠네
그여자 오늘 아침엔 어떻던가? 괜찮았죠. 별일 없었어요
아직도 그 여자 정신상태를걱정하고 있는건가?
아뇨, 나아졌어요확실히 나아졌죠
감시자로서 간섭하면 안된다는자네 역할은 이해하도록 하게
감시자레
그래도 내가 알아야될만한정보가 있다면은..
어떤거라도..
뭔가 있다면말씀드리겠습니다
오, 젠장, 그 녀석이야안돼, 전화 받지마
안돼!여보세요?
베스, 너 어디야?
밖에당신은 어딘데?
우리 얘기 좀 해
무슨 얘기?집으로 와주면 좋겠는데
그게, 난 아닌거 같거든
뭔가 알고 있어
그, 너 돌아가면 안돼너도 알잖아
그래, 못가
오, 망할오, 이런 세상에
폴이 날 쫓아서키아라를 봤어
지금 별로인가?
날 지져놓고
날 두들겨패고그렇다고 내가 그냥
내가 그냥물러날줄 안거야?
아무것도 아닌 것처럼?나 일하고 있었어
어, 그래?
그래, 니가 모든걸망처버리려고 했었지
그래? 지금 니 역할을한번 맞춰보지, 어, 사라?
그리고, 코크,나한테서 훔쳐간거 말야
죽은척 하고 있으면
그걸로 누가떨어질줄 알았어?
어?
파우치가내 손가락을 가져갔지
내가 1만 5천을
가지고 나타나지 않으면..날 바닷가재로 만들어 버릴꺼야
매주 손가락 하나씩,바닷가재 발톱 하나만 남을때까지
앉아, 앉아있어너 필요한거 돈이지, 아니야?
빅, 저기 2만이야..1만5천은 빚갚고
그럼 5천은너 고통받고 고생한거
이것도 분명무슨 연극이겠지
꺼져버리란 돈이야, 됐어?뭐 넌 알 것도 없고
난 모든 걸 알자격이 있어
내 질문 하나 할까?너 어떻게 한거지?
저 영안실에 누워서
숨도 참고있었지, 사라
내가 고함을 지르면서
빌어먹을 어린애처럼울부짖고 있었는데..
미치겠는게뭔지 알아?
내가 얼마나멍청한지 너 알지?
내가 여기서서널 보면서
계속 생각나는건머어틀 해변이야
너 기억나?그래, 아주
오래전 일이지, 빅난 그 무크족 앤젤하고
일하던 때지. 넌 쇼장에서 일했었고그때 우리가 자랑스럽지 않거든
우린 세상의 정점에 있었다고, 사라우린 기생충이였어
아니, 우린 사랑했었어난 아니야
절대로
할말 다한거 같은데빅터
저 돈 원해?
당장 챙겨 나가
지금 당장, 빅!
알았다
끝난거 아니야사라
니 인생에 남자들은 전부나 빼놓고 완전 재수탱이들인거야?
S 부인 집에나 대신 좀 가줘
키아라 잘 있는지 봐줘알았지?
너 폴 집에돌아가면 안돼
놈이 내 딸을 협박하는데그냥 둘 수 없어
사라, 폴 집에 돌아가면안된다고! 사라!
아니, 괜찮아요걱정마세요
뭐 다른 일 생기면알려드리죠
필릭스가 전화했어?그래
그냥 녹음한거 틀어주더라나 다 들었어
넌 어디야?이제 들어가려고
가서 폴 알들을 쏴버릴꺼야잠깐만, 사라
이번이 우리가 해답을얻을 기회야
놈이 키아라까지쫓아왔어, 코즈
알아, 안다고그래도, 널 감싸주기도 했지
맞지? 그 올리비에란 작자뭐 잘못된거 있는지 물었는데
폴은 없다고 그랬어왜일까?
그야 녀석이 가짜 베스한테빠져들고 있어서겠지
그래! 끝내주잖아! 그건..
니가 이용하면 된다고내가 어쩌다가
이 진창에 처음 발을들여놓게 됐는데, 어?
좋아, 알았어열 좀 식히고
올리비에란 작자가 녀석을굴리는거 같은데, 이건 꼭
이중 눈속임 같거든너 뭘 얘기하려는건데?
그들이 폴한테도숨기는게 있다고
맞아? 그러니 녀석도실험결과에 손을 못 대고
그 자식도 자기가 감시하는게복제인간인지 모른단거야?
그래, 그렇지
하지만 올리비에는확실히 알아
알았어? 그자가 바로우리가 잡아야되는 놈이야
내가 폴부터 먼저처리하면 안될까?
사라?
난 쇼파에서 잘께
도니, 도니, 도니..
당신이 맞아
다들 사생활이필요하지
이리와
네 권총은 반납한줄 알았는데어?
왼쪽 자켓 주머니
내려놔
저기, 나한테스토커가 붙었나본데
앉아
그건 탁자에 놓고
알고 있었어
딱 집어내진 못했지만알고는 있었어
네가 청문회 하기로했었던 날이였지
몇 달만에 처음으로 우리 섹스하고뭐가? 당신이 그리웠던거야
넌 그 크래쉬 티셔츠를입고 있었어
나는 꼭.. 뭐야?
그러더니, 쿵, 넌 나랑바로 저 조리대에서 했지
불만있는거야, 폴?무..무슨 얘길 하는거야?
생각하던거 조차도
거부하더니니가 밀어붙인거야
나 요즘 어땠는지너도 알잖아
그러더니 니 목에 있던 상처가사라졌더라고, 뭐 때문일까?
무슨 크림?
그리고 이 번엔..
이 꼬마 여자애
난 베스가 아이를가질 수 없다는걸
알았을 때곁에 있었어
그럼 이 여자앤 뭐지?
걘 이복동생이야둘이 있는걸 지켜봤지
걘 니 딸이야아니라고?
정신나간거야?내가?
그, 내가 오늘옛날 비디오를 좀 봤지
니가 단축 마라톤을준비할 때였지
니가 마지막으로 참가했던경기가 뭐였지?
어느 도시에서 열린거지?
베스 어딨어?
이게 마지막이야
니가 누구던지 간에..
베스는 어딨어?
그애 자살했어
기차 앞으로뛰어들었지
넌 영국인이네
넌 누구야?
난 걔 쌍둥이야
쌍둥이?
무슨 시험하는거야?
무슨 시험 말야?
베스한테자매는 없어
니 이름이 뭐야?
사라
사라 뭐?
사라면 충분하잖아
베스가 죽고서내가 걔 신분을 챙겼어
베스는 죽지 않았어
이봐, 난 걔 은행계좌만챙겨가려고 했던거야
너랑 얽히려던 생각은전혀 없었다고
정말 그애가 죽었다면니가 죽이지 않았단걸 어떻게 알아?
니가 그앨 죽였으니까뭐라고?
너가 걔 감시자잖아아니야?
그래서 그게 뭐?
니가 걜 관찰했지
니가 사람들을집에 들였고
어제밤 처럼
의사들이 와서 그 애가잠든 동안 의학실험을 했지
그 애도 알았어
넌 심어진거잖아또, 그 애가 자살한건
자기가 사랑했던 남자가자기 삶 전부를 거짓으로 만들어버렸으니까
니가 자길 사랑하지 않는걸 알았지만니가 왜 떠나지 않는지는
이해하지 못했지그리고는 그애도 알게된거야
그럴리 없어
이건 시험이야
안그래?
아니냐고?
그 앤 널 믿었어
그 애한테어떻게 그럴 수 있지?
나라고 방법이있었을거 같에?
왜인지만 말해줘
우리한텐왜인지 말을 안해주거든
We're clones.
We're someone's experimentand they're killing us off!
I'm not Beth.
Beth was on this killer'shit list and, now, I am.
Someone is covering up their illegalexperiments by wiping us out.
If Sarah misses tonight, thenshe may never get Kira back.
She want me to impersonate herin front of her daughter?
- You're not my mother.- I'm sorry about this,
but it's very importantthat you keep this a secret.
If that was my boyfriend, I'djust in front of a train too.
Something's different.
- Everything all right here?- Does she seem all right to you?
Look, we need to spend sometime together, figure out what's
suddenly going on with us,because most of it I like a lot.
Sarah blindsided me,then she took off with the coke.
I'm on the hook with Pouchy!
Maggie helped make you.
Beth killed her to protect us.
We have a connection.Can you feel it?
Go. Run!
I quit.
- Shh. Shh, shh, shh.- Tomas.
Easy now.
Sleep, child.
Sleep.
So, the killer'sstill out there.
Yeah, probably crawled back to thefreak that sent her after us.
Did you have to quitbeing a cop?
- How can that help?- Alison, this isn't
why I called.I want to thank you
for helping with Kira.
Oh.
Yeah, I get to see hertomorrow,
- and, uh, you set that up, so...- Well, she's a special little girl.
I can tell. You're very lucky.
No.
- Hey!- Beth! Stop, it's me!
- Oh, my God. You asshole!- You'd stab me in the eye with a nail file?
Yeah, you sneak up on me in the shower, I amgonna stab you in the eye with a nail file!
Aren't you supposed to beat Cody's?
I didn't mean to scare you.I'm sorry.
How sorry are you?
Beth.
Get in.
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
Beth.
Mm.
Let's go away.
You're off the force.
I hate my job.
Let's pack our bags.
Right now.
I'm serious.
Let's talk about itin the morning.
It's on the scanner.She's coming out.
Let's get her down.
Now! Just put it in now!
♪ ooh ooh ooh ooh ♪
Orphan Black 01x05Conditions of Existence
Original Air Date  April 27, 2013
♪ ah ah ♪
♪ ooh ooh ooh ♪
Hey, you want coffee?
Uh, no thanks.
How you feeling?
What?
No gun, no badge,nowhere to be.
- Mm-hmm.- Let's leave.
We don't have any ties.
I have three simple wordsfor you:
- Paul.- Rio de Janeiro.
I can't just leave nowand think about going to Rio.
Why not?
It's what you wanted, right?Commitment. I'm ready.
No, I can't thinkabout this right now.
- What's wrong?- Nothing's wrong.
You're shaking like a leaf.
- Where are you going?- I'm just going out for some air.
Ok?
It's an electrode froman electroencephalogram array
a what?
An EEG helmet. It monitorselectrical activity in the brain.
So it wasn't a bloody dream,then, was it?
I knew it.Well, how long
have I been saying this? We're likelab rats in an illegal experiment.
Sarah, where was Paulduring all this?
Uh... there were doctors,
um, two or three of them.He could be
in on it, though.Maybe he set it up.
Well, somebody must be watchingthe lab rats... someone we know.
Well, I mean, if it weremy experiment, yeah, I would
Put an observerclose to the subject...
You know, somebody to keep tabsand accumulate data.
Cosima...What'd they do to me?
I think you'd know
if they'd done anythingreally... um, invasive.
- Oh, my God.-  I'm just saying, um,
An EEG is likea neurological test,
and that mark on your arm lookslike... a blood sample.
- It sounds diagnostic.- With Paul in on it?
- I don't know.- Why?
- Just 'cause he slept with you?- Fee.
Yeah, we sort ofended up shagging.
Dude, that's complex.
You sleptwith Beth's boyfriend?
Oh.
Far be it from me.
I may be sleepingwith my spy as well.
There's the gun you wanted.I've gotta go.
Hey, hey, where's the money?
What's it for?
It's the self-defense fund,yeah?
Last time I checked,I'm the only one defending us.
Here's 20,000.
Please use it wisely.
Yeah, I'll bring youthe receipt.
I am gonna shootPaul's balls off.
Wait, just, um,just squeeze them, ok?
He's our wayinto this whole thing.
But if my blind subject weresuddenly to become...
Self-aware, it'd either bea Eureka moment or...
Yeah?
I would terminate, so...
- Be careful, ok?- On that note...
Shit.
- Cop station. Third time today.- No, don't answer that.
- Uh, Art, what do you want?- It's Raj.
Mmm...
I'm off the force, Raj.
I know. You ok?
- Yeah.- Ok, well, you know
That surveillance shitthat I lent you?
I'm gonna need that backbefore they inventory.
Surveillance shit?Right. Right.
And, Beth, level with me.
This is just about Paul,right?
Look, I'll get back to youin a couple days, ok?
So, Beth hadsurveillance equipment.
So then she was on to Paul too.
did she find anything?
It's critical.
One week she's fine,the next it's armageddon.
No, I understand that,but I don't want to give her
any reason to react.
Well, you tell me!
If it gets any worse,what are our options?
- What are you doing?- I have to call you back.
Why... why were youin my vanity?
I need... scissors.
Who were you talking to?
- Just now?- Mm-hmm.
- Uh, Big Rich, from work.- About me?
About Susan Teller.She's all over us this quarter.
You know that.
Oh, good. Um, can youcut this tag off?
It's driving me crazy.
Much better.
All right, what do we doif he walks in?
Shoot him.
I'm kidding.
Just... find the surveillancestuff, yeah?
And put everything backwhere you found it.
This place is antiseptic.
Paul's whole world feels fakenow.
What?
I don't leave printswhen I burgle.
Trexcom Consulting.
If, uh, fake Paul wasobserving Beth,
what makes you so certain noone's observing Sarah Manning?
Who? Mrs. S hates me.I haven't seen her in a year.
And I'm giving you the benefitof the doubt.
A ringing vote of confidence.
Nothing on Beth's computer.Nothing.
No audio files, no video,no transcripts.
Holy shit.
Hey, hey. Hey.
He's military.
Looks like you're notthe only one keeping secrets.
What are those?
Letters from Beth.
- To Paul? I want to read them.- Uh, uh, uh.
No, they're private.
Where the hell isthis surveillance stuff?
Don't know.We've searched everywhere.
There we go.
She wasn't messing around,was she?
Maybe it's timeto find out where Paul works.
Oh, yeah.Trexcom Consulting.
Fake Paul, fake company.
I bet you moneythere's nothing there.
No way.
Beth.
We downsized, remember?
Paul's office is over here now.
Oh, right.
Yeah, of course.
He's in a meeting.
Oh. Y... you know what,
um... we kinda got into itthis morning.
I brought up some lunchas a peace offering.
Come on.
I'll just...
Sure.
Big Boob Blowies?
Felix, I hope
you can hear this. Yes! Yeah, I can.
Now, you silly bitch, would youget your fanny out of there?
- You brought me lunch.- Yeah.
Olive branch.
- Beth, this morning... - You want to talk about it?
I'd rather talkabout last night
- in the shower. - Paul.
I came to bring you lunch,that's all.
Something's changed with us.
Mmm.
I know you can feel it.
What happened to your scar?
What?
The scar on your neck from the mountain bike crash.
It's gone.
Oh. Really?
I-I'm using a new lotion.
Let me see.
You will try anything,won't you?
I will.
But I gotta get back to work.
Thanks for lunch.
- See you tonight.- Ok.
Madison.
Clear my afternoon, ok?
- Something came up. - Shit.
Alison, what are you doing?
Uh...
What's in the box, Donnie?
It's private.
No, it isn't!What... what is in it?
- Donnie, what's in the box?- I am entitled to a little privacy,
- even in this house.- Oh, that's rich coming from you.
- What hell is that supposed to mean?- Open the box, Donnie!
- Give it to me!- Open it!
Alison... Alison, stop it!
Yeah, blood looks fine.No infection.
What kind of symptomsare we talking about?
Um... shortness of breath,coughing up blood...
That sort of thing.
- Who's the subject?- Uh, subjects, and if I told you that,
- I'd have to kill you.- Ha! Ha...
Ha! Ha! Um, can you run
a PCR on these samples,see if there are any
- genetic markers?- You're thinking...
Antitrypsin deficiency?Cystic fibrosis?
Yeah, that kind of thing.
And, um, can you sequencefor Cytochrome C?
- The barcode gene?- Mm-hmm.
That's the one we usefor species differentiation.
Is it?
What's in it for me?
Um, how about you getto have sex... with yourself?
Aw-awesome deal.
Arrete. Arrete, je te dis.
C'est difficile pour moi aussi.
Oui.
Non, non. Tu ne peux pas venir ici, parce...
Parce... parce que j'aidu boulot, parce que... allez.
Allez, il faut que j'y aille.
I'm sorry.
He's a bastard.
Who?
Paul. Beth loved him,
but he wouldn't love her backand he wouldn't leave her.
Mm. Well, he's certainlychanged his tune now, hasn't he?
Sarah, he's falling for you.
God, what a mess.
I'm outside Kira's school.
Of all the things that scare meright now, Fee,
- this one's the heaviest. - You know she can't wait
- to see you, right?- Yeah, thanks.
She's the only thingthat really matters, you know?
I know.Um, give her my love, ok?
- Colin.- Hi.
- So glad you could step away.- From the morgue?
Uh, trust me, scheduling isn'treally an issue.
Hi.
It's me this time.
I know.
God, I missed you so much.
I missed you too.
Why are you wearingsuch fancy clothes?
Ah...
You don't miss a thing,do you?
Are you ok, mommy?
Yeah.
I am now.
God, you're so big.
I'm the smallest kidin my class.
Well, you're big to me.
How come you never told meabout Auntie Alison?
I didn't know her.
She looks just like you.
Yeah.
One day, I'll explain it allto you. Yeah, monkey?
Is someone tryingto hurt us?
Why do you ask that?
Alison said you're making surewe're safe.
Hey. Hey.
No.
You're safe, Kira.I promise.
Ok?
You coming in?
Hey. Sorry.
You just forgot thisin the lab. Sorry.
Thank you.
I, um, did peek.
You're French.
You have killers grades.
Thank you.
Um, um, oh, God.I am so sorry.
I'm not usuallylike... like this.
Oh. Bad breakup?
Yeah, well, we'rean ocean apart, so...
Yeah.Long distance never works.
Um, you'rein microbiology too, right?
Yes. Um, immunology. I studyhost-parasite relationships.
Oh, cool, cool.Yeah, I'm evo-devo.
Evolutionary development.
Yeah, yeah. That's... that'swhat we call it here.
- Yeah.- Yeah.
- Delphine.- Cosima.
- Enchantee.- Enchantee.
You're so independent,aren't you?
Hmm, monkey?
- Little monkey?- Remind you of anyone?
Yeah, but I was much angrier,wasn't I?
Even small.
You were the one who introducedme to punk rock, though.
Yeah. You tookall of the attitude,
none of the politics.
I'm just happy she doesn't haveto bounce around like I did.
I was her age when I cameto live with you
- in London, yeah?- A little bit older.
Well, you got me this far.
I know that.
I still need your help, though.
Ah.
I need you to tell me, uh...
what you reallyknow about me...
Where I came from.
- Why now?- I'm trying to square things away.
For Kira, you know?
You were part of the fostersystem. I took in kids.
You know, I don't knowwho your parents were.
Yeah, I talked to...Family Services
in Brixton already,but I just wondered if there's
- anything else.- Is everything ok?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm fine.
What about Vic?
- Vic still in the picture?- God no.
That much I can promise.Vic is done.
Ok!
How you doing, boss?Nice to see you,
Pouchy.
Pouchy, she jumpedin front of a train.
I don't even know whyshe did it, all right?
Sure, we had our ups and downs,but everything was fine.
She had the coke on her.
So I'm thinking maybe the cops
have it.Give me one week.
Pouchy. I'll get you your money.
You say that last week!
I know. I'm good for it,though. Wait a minute!
I'm good for it, Pouchy.You know me. Pouchy, please.
Wait a minute, Pouchy. One more week.I'll get you your money, man! Ok!
Ok! Ok!
Pouchy, please! One more week,man! Ok, give me a minute!
Ok! All right! Ok! All right!
Ok! You want money? Ok! Ok! Give me a minute!I just need to...
I'm good.
Ok.
One chocolate bar each.
That's it.
Ok.
Hold your sister's hand.
Ok? And don't talk to anybody.
- Ok.- Ok, mom.
I love you.
- Love you too.- Ok, mom.
Uh, deterrence,or surveillance?
Surveillance, please.
Something small.
You mean something like,uh, this? Wireless, discreet,
they call it the nanny cam.
Sometimes the nanny'spinching your valuables;
sometimes your husband'spinching the nanny, you know?
Just show mehow it works, please.
Stay in school.
I mean it, buddy.
Sarah?
Sarah.
Hey, Sarah.
Sarah, you're alive!
Sarah, it's me!
Look at me.
Uh, I-I don't...
I don't know who you are.
- You bitch, you faked it?- You've got the wrong person.
You faked it, you bitch!How could you do this to me?!
Sarah, I thought you were dead!
How could you goddamn do thisto me? Ah! Ahh!
My eyes! Aw, you bitch!
Aw! Ah!
- Ahhh! Goddamn it!- Ah, there they are.
- Goddamn! Die!- Ok. It's a race. Into the car.
- It's a race to get into the car.- Sarah!
Ok, whoever gets in first wins!
- Who's that guy?- Ah! Sarah!
Ok.
You bitch!
- Hello. Alison.- I was just assaulted
By a disgusting thugwho thought I was you.
- Who? What'd he look like?- I don't know. He was...
Urban.
What the hell does that mean?
Not white, ok?
Oh, shit. Vic?
What happened?
I assaulted him backis what happened.
Please tell methat's not Kira's father.
No, no, absolutely not.
Well, what's going onwith Paul?
Well, we think Beth was spyingon him.
We found surveillance gear.
She never told me about that.
Is it true? Is he a mole?
I don't know that yet.
What's going on with you?
Nothing, I'm fine.
Call me when you knowsomething for sure.
Olivier.
Paul.
What are you doing here?Is something wrong?
We need to talk about Beth.
How was she this morning?
Fine.
Everything's fine.
You don't dothis sort of thing much, do you?
You mean with a live person?
Oh! Ha!
Morgue humor.
You're awfully cute.
- Ok.- Ok.
Ok, bye.
Bye.
The morgue attendant? Really?
- Can you knock?- Brilliant, Fee.
Shagging the bloke that weconned into identifying my body.
Colin is the first nice boyI've met in ages.
What, like six weeks?
- No. At least eight.- Where do you think
- this is gonna go, eh?- Oh, my God.
Oh, I'm so sorry. I completely forgetThat your life is always
- more important than mine.- No, it's just
way more difficult.Vic is back.
Oh, shit.
Yeah, he ran into Alison,so he thinks I'm alive.
I'll figure it out. I'll...I need to know
- what happened at Paul's office.- Sorry. I've been a bit busy, Haven't I?
Well, I did record something.
What are you doing here?Is something wrong?
This is it.
We need to talk about Beth.
- How was she this morning? - Fine. Everything's fine.
Are you still concerned about her mental health?
No. She's better, certainly better.
You understand your role as monitor is not to interfere.
Monitor.
But if there's anythingpertinent I should know...
Anything at all...
If there were, I would tell you.
- Oh, shit. It's him.- No, don't answer that.
- No!- Hello?
Beth. Where are you?
Out. Where are you?
We have to talk.
- About what?- I need you to come home.
Yeah, I don't think so.
He know something.
Well, you can't go back there.You know that.
No, I can't.
- Oh, shit.- Oh, my God.
Paul followed mestraight to Kira.
Is this a bad time?
You tase me,
you mace me,but you think I'm just gonna...
I'm just gonna walk away
- like I'm nobody?- I was working a job.
Oh. Yeah?
Yeah, you would'veruined the whole thing.
Yeah? Guess you're on a rollnow, huh, Sarah?
And that cokethat you stole from me.
Pretending to be dead.
Who do you thinktook the fall for that?
Huh?
Pouchy took my finger.
If I don't come up
with 15k....he's gonna lobster me.
A finger every week until allI have left is a lobster claw.
- Sit down. Sit down.- Do you want the money, or not?
Vic. That's 20k...15 for your debt,
and then five for yourpain and suffering.
That must havebeen some play.
Mmmmm.
This is "piss off" money, ok?You don't get to know anything.
I'm entitledto know everything.
Can I ask you a question?How do you do it?
Lying there in that morgue.
Holding your breath, Sarah,
while I am bawling,
I'm cryinglike a goddamn child.
You know what's crazy?
You know how stupid I am?
I'm standing herelooking at you,
and I keep thinking aboutis Myrtle Beach.
- You remember?- Yeah, that was
- a long time ago, Vic.- I was working with that mook,
- Angel. You had your in with the carnies.- I'm not proud of what we did.
- We were on top of the world, Sarah.- We were parasites.
- No, we were in love.- Not me.
Ever.
I think she means it, Victor.
You want that money?
Take it and go now.
Right now, Vic!
Ok.
This is not over, Sarah.
Is every man in your lifea complete wanker except me?
I need you togo to S's house.
Make sure Kira's ok, yeah?
You're not goingback to Paul's.
I will not let himthreaten my daughter.
Sarah, you're not goingback to Paul's! Sarah!
No, it's fine. Don't worry.
If anything else comes up,I'll let you know.
- Felix called you?- Yeah.
He just played me the recording.I heard everything.
- Where are you?- I'm about to go in
- and shoot Paul in the balls.- Wait, Sarah.
This is our chanceto get answers.
He followed me to Kira, Cos.
I know, I know,but he also covered for you.
Right? That Olivier guy,he asked if anything was wrong,
and Paul said no. Why?
'Cause I think he may befalling for fake Beth.
Yes! That's awesome! That...
- You can use that.- What do you think
Got me into this messin the first place, huh?
Ok, I know. Just chill.
I think that Oliver guy,he runs Paul. It sounds like
- some kind of double blind.- What are you going on about?
They are keeping Paulin the dark too.
Right? So that he can'tskew the results either.
You mean he may not even knowhe's watching a clone?
Yes, right.
But Olivier definitely knows.
Ok? He's the onethat we need to get to.
You mind if I getthrough Paul first?
Sarah?
I'll sleep on the couch.
Donnie. Donnie, Donnie...
You're right.
Everyone deserves their privacy.
Come.
- I thought you handed in your sidearm.- Huh?
Left jacket pocket,
hanging low.
Well, apparentlyI've got a stalker.
Sit.
Put it on the table.
I knew.
I couldn't put my fingeron it, but I knew.
It was that day you weresupposed to do the hearing,
- first time we had sex in months.- What? I missed you.
You were wearingthat clash t-shirt.
I was like, what?
And then, wham, you screw meright on the kitchen counter.
Are you complaining, Paul?What are you saying?
You quite the force
after refusingever even to think it.
You know what I'vebeen through.
And then the scar on your neckjust disappears because of what?
Some cream?
And now...
This little girl.
I was there whenBeth found out
she couldn't have kids.
So who was this girl?
- She's my half-sister.- I watched you together.
She's your daughter,isn't she?
- You're losing it.- Am I?
Well, I was lookingat some old video today.
You were trainingfor that half marathon.
What was the last raceyou were in?
What city was it in?
Where is Beth?
One last time.
Whoever you are...
where is Beth?
She killed herself.
She jumpedin front of a train.
You're English.
Who are you?
I'm her twin.
Twin?
Is this a test?
A test of what?
Beth didn't have a sister.
What's your name?
Sarah.
Sarah what?
Sarah's good enough.
When Beth died,I took her identity.
Beth isn't dead.
Look, I was just gonnaclean out her bank accounts.
I didn't mean to getall tangled up with you.
If she really is dead, how doI know you didn't kill her?
- 'Cause you killed her.- What?
You're her monitor,aren't you?
And what's that?
You observe her.
You let people into her home.
Like last night.
Doctors came and medicallyexamined her in her sleep.
And she knew.
You're a plant,and she killed herself
because the man that she lovedturned her whole life into a lie.
She knew you didn't love her,and she couldn't understand
why you wouldn't leave.And now she figured it out.
This isn't true.
This is a test.
Isn't it?
She trusted you.
How could you do that to her?
You think I had a choice?
Just tell me why.
They don't tell us why.